The law's reach never stretched this far.
The Naked Gun is a action, comedy, crime film directed by Akiva Schaffer.
Only one man has the particular set of skills...
to lead Police Squad and save the world: Lt.
Frank Drebin Jr.
Following in his father's footsteps, he must solve a murder
case to prevent Police Squad from closure.
Frank Drebin Jr., played by Liam Neeson.
Beth Davenport, played by Pamela Anderson.
Ed Hocken Jr., played by Paul Walter Hauser.
Richard Cane, played by Danny Huston.
Chief Davis, played by CCH Pounder.
Sig Gustafson, played by Kevin Durand.
The Naked Gun is a 2025 American action comedy parody film directed by Akiva
Schaffer, who co-wrote the screenplay with Dan Gregor and Doug Mand.
The fourth film in the Naked Gun franchise, it stars Liam Neeson in the main role, with Pamela
Anderson, Paul Walter Hauser, Kevin Durand, and Danny Huston in supporting roles.
Its plot follows the son of Lt.
Frank Drebin who must succeed in his father's footsteps
to prevent the closure of Police Squad.
A fourth Naked Gun film was announced in 2009, as a direct-to-TV sequel starring Leslie Nielsen, with Alan Spencer being
attached to write; however, the project was cancelled due to Spencer's departure, and Nielsen died in November 2010.
After several years of development, including being redeveloped as a reboot starring Ed Helms in 2013, it was announced in
January 2021 that Seth MacFarlane had been hired to develop the project, and he expressed interest in casting Neeson.
Although MacFarlane was hired to direct, Schaffer replaced him after the
film was greenlit in October 2022, and Neeson was cast.
Anderson was cast in April 2024, and further casting took place the
following month, when filming began in Atlanta, Georgia.
Filming wrapped that June.
The Naked Gun premiered at the SVA Theater in Manhattan on July 28, 2025, and was
released in the United States by Paramount Pictures on August 1, 2025.
It received positive reviews from critics and grossed $102.1
million worldwide on a $42 million budget.
The film explores themes of sequel, slapstick comedy,
spoof, reboot, aftercreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted.